The hero we need now.
The Toxic Avenger Unrated is a action, comedy, science
fiction film directed by Macon Blair.
When a downtrodden janitor, Winston Gooze, is exposed to a catastrophic toxic
accident, he’s transformed into a new kind of hero: The Toxic Avenger.
Now, Toxie must rise from outcast to savior, taking on ruthless corporate overlords and
corrupt forces who threaten his son, his friends, and his community.
Winston / Toxie, the Hero, played by Peter Dinklage.
Wade, the Kid, played by Jacob Tremblay.
J.J. Doherty, the Wild Card, played by Taylour Paige.
Kissy Sturnevan, his Associate, played by Julia Davis.
Thad Barkabus, the Big Boss, played by Jonny Coyne.
Fritz Garbinger, his Creepy Brother, played by Elijah Wood.
The Toxic Avenger Unrated is a 2023 American superhero black
comedy film written and directed by Macon Blair.
It is the fifth installment, a reboot of The Toxic Avenger
film series, and a remake of the 1984 film.
The film stars Peter Dinklage as the title character, alongside Jacob Tremblay,
Taylour Paige, Julia Davis, Jonny Coyne, Elijah Wood, and Kevin Bacon.
The Toxic Avenger premiered as the opening film of Fantastic Fest on September 21, 2023, with a wider theatrical
release followed by Cineverse and Iconic Events Releasing in the United States for August 29, 2025.
The film has received positive reviews from critics and it
grossed $3.4 million at the box office.
The film explores themes of high school, new
jersey, police, single parent, alcohol.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.